<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>Barry Pitman</title>
 <link href="http://barrypitman.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://barrypitman.github.com"/>
 <updated>2013-01-18T15:41:25+01:00</updated>
 <id>http://barrypitman.github.com</id>
 <author>
   <name>Barry Pitman</name>
   <email>barrypitman@gmail.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>CSS Background Image to DataURI translation at runtime</title>
   <link href="http://barrypitman.github.com/2011/06/17/runtime-image-to-datauri-in-css"/>
   <updated>2011-06-17T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://barrypitman.github.com/2011/06/17/runtime-image-to-datauri-in-css</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_URI_scheme&quot;&gt;Data URI's&lt;/a&gt; are a method of embedding inline data in web page responses.
For instance, using data URIs, a background image can be embedded within a
CSS file, reducing the number of requests that must be made to the originating server.
According to Yahoo’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://developer.yahoo.com/yslow/&quot;&gt;YSlow&lt;/a&gt; tool, minimizing HTTP requests is number one on the list of
'Web Performance Best Practices and Rules'.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A data URI is a string representation of a file’s contents (base64 encoded), with the following format:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;data:[&amp;lt;MIME-type&amp;gt;][;charset=&amp;lt;encoding&amp;gt;][;base64],&amp;lt;data&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;e.g. a small red dot in an &lt;img&gt; tag:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;img src=&quot;data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAUA
AAAFCAYAAACNbyblAAAAHElEQVQI12P4//8/w38GIAXDIBKE0DHxgljNBAAO
9TXL0Y4OHwAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==&quot; alt=&quot;Red dot&quot;/&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;as opposed to&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;img src=&quot;../images/red_dot.png&quot; alt'&quot;Red dot&quot;/&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using base64 encoding will increase the size of the image by 1/3, but that increase can be offset by
gzipping the response (and you’ll be making fewer requests). &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_URI_scheme&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;
has a good section on the pros/cons
of using data URI’s. One serious disadvantage is that older browsers, e.g. IE &amp;lt; 7, don’t support data URIs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Data URIs as background images&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data URIs are normally embedded in files which are meant to be cached by the brower. One common use-case
is replacing background images references in CSS files to data URIs, e.g.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;.warningImage {
    background: url('data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACAAAAAgCAIAAAD8GO2jAAAACXBIWXMAAC4jAA...=') no-repeat;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;instead of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;.warningImage {
    background: url('../images/icon_warning_32x32.png') no-repeat;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This method has similar benefits to using &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alistapart.com/articles/sprites&quot;&gt;'image sprites'&lt;/a&gt;,
but also has &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nczonline.net/blog/2010/07/06/data-uris-make-css-sprites-obsolete/&quot;&gt;several advantages&lt;/a&gt; over them.
In many cases, background images are small icons, background gradients etc. which are well suited
to be replaced with data URIs. I noticed that Google is using both techniques on their search results
pages; the Google logo and other icons are served as an image sprite, while dynamic images/thumbnails
are served as data-uri images inline with the content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The primary advantage of data URI background images over image sprites is that they are easier to maintain.
Still, I’d argue that maintaining them won’t be breeze; you’ll have to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;maintain two copies of the css file (one with links, one with data URIs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a copy of the image&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;keep them in sync over time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;serve the data URI version to browsers which support them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;There are several online tools which can assist by converting your images to data URIs,
but wouldn’t it be nice to be able to automatically convert background images at runtime and
serve the right version automatically?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Runtime replacement of background-images with data URIs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have implemented a Java servlet filter
(&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/barrypitman/CSS-data-URI-substitution-filter&quot;&gt;source available on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;)
which dynamically 'includes' background images that are referenced from CSS files as data URIs.
Using this filter alleviates the burden of maintaining two separate sets of CSS files; you only
need one have one CSS file and the filter will include background images if the user agent supports
them at runtime. Simply put, it includes/inlines background images by performing server-side includes
on the image references at runtime, using&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;httpServletRequest.getRequestDispatcher(backgroundImageUrl).include(httpServletRequest, wrappedResponse);
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously the filter should only be mapped to CSS files that you’d like to perform this tranformation on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The filter operates as follows:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check the the user agent supports data URIs. If not, skip filter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wrap the response to the CSS file request with a custom ServletResponseWrapper which captures the response in a
CharArrayWriter instead of streaming it back to the client (so we can modify it later).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pass the request along the filter chain, i.e. &lt;code&gt;filterChain.doFilter(httpServletRequest, wrappedResponse);&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extract the response as a string. At this point we have the contents of the CSS file as a string.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using regex, find references to background images within the CSS contents.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For each reference to a background image url (e.g. '../images/button.gif'):&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wrap the response with a new custom ServletResponseWrapper which captures the response in a new ByteArrayOutputStream&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the request dispatcher to 'include' the referenced image, i.e.
&lt;code&gt;request.getRequestDispatcher(backgroundImageUrl).include(httpServletRequest, imageResponseWrapper);&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extract the image contents as a byte[] from the wrapped response&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using the filename and byte[], convert the image to a data URI representation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Replace the reference to backgroud image url in the CSS file contents (from top-level step 4) with its data URI
representation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Note: if a step above fails (e.g. 404 for the image), we leave the original reference intact.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write the modified CSS file contents back to the client.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Obviously the regex used to match extract the image URLs from the contents of the CSS file is an
important part of this process. Getting it wrong could cause one to mess up the returned CSS
content badly! The patten which I have so far (which could probably be improved upon) is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;\bbackground(-image)?:\s*url\(['|&quot;]?(.*?)['|&quot;]?\)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the pattern above, the filter will ignore image URLs that appear to reference
external images (e.g. on other sites) as well as images that are already in data URI format.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have tested this filter on some fairly large CSS files, including a  minized version of the
jQuery UI stylesheet, and it was able to replace all background image references with their data
URI representation without problems. It has been tested in Jetty and Tomcat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The filter could easily be extended to be able to include other types of content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The filter assumes that the background url is the first listed style attribute,
so it will replace &lt;code&gt;background: url(img.gif) #FFF&lt;/code&gt; but not &lt;code&gt;background: #FFF url(img.gif)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It can only include images that can be served by the application; i.e. references to images on external
domains will be ignored.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The filter can be configured to not replace references to background images whose size is larger than a
certain value, e.g. 32KB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Because the filter dynamically modifies the response by including images, changes to the actual images
will not cause the last-modified headers of the CSS file to be updated; you'll need to &lt;code&gt;touch&lt;/code&gt; the CSS file as
well if you want client to fetch a new version after modifying an image.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be aware that embedding large background images in style sheets can have an adverse effect on page
rendering; essentially your images will be loaded much sooner that if you left them as URL references.
See this article for a great explanation. Obviously the idea is that you cache the larger CSS file,
so as long as the CSS file is already in the cache, you won’t have that problem.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Preventing XSS attacks with AntiSamy (Part 2)</title>
   <link href="http://barrypitman.github.com/2011/04/22/safe-and-clean-HTML-output-with-antisamy"/>
   <updated>2011-04-22T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://barrypitman.github.com/2011/04/22/safe-and-clean-HTML-output-with-antisamy</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My &lt;a href=&quot;/2011/04/14/using-input-validation-XSS&quot;&gt;last blog post&lt;/a&gt; discussed one method of protecting your web
application against Cross-Site Scripting (XSS) attacks; by filtering all user input with an
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/barrypitman/antisamy-servlet-filter&quot;&gt;AntiSamy servlet filter&lt;/a&gt;
during request processing. In this post I’d like to discuss an alternative/complementary method involving AntiSamy;
filtering HTML-formatted content during response processing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Recap&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To protect users from XSS attacks we should escape user-supplied inputs using e.g. &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;c:out/&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tags in JSP files.
We can’t escape HTML-formatted content with ‘&amp;lt;c:out/&gt;’ tags because we’d be escaping the formatting as well.
We need an intelligent library like AntiSamy to decide what formatting to allow and what to remove
(based on a well-defined policy).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When displaying user-supplied HTML-formatted content to a user, XSS attacks are not the only thing we need to
worry about. Imagine how this input: &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; could potentially mess up your layout! Fortunately AntiSamy
will also check for unclosed tags and remove/close them for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Solution&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The solution is implemented as a JSP custom tag, making it simple to re-use. Using it in a JSP file might look like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;safeHtml:out text=&quot;${someBean.htmlTextToRender}&quot;/&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can also offer the developer the option of using a custom AntiSamy policy file:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src='https://gist.github.com/4557487.js?file=SafeHtmlTag.java'&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;/&lt;em&gt;*
 * JSP tag that renders AntiSamy-filtered HTML, useful for displaying HTML markup in a safe way.
 *
 * @author barry pitman
 * @since 2011/04/14 1:26 PM
 &lt;/em&gt;/
public class SafeHtmlTag extends TagSupport {&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;private static final long serialVersionUID = 1L;
private static final Logger LOG = Logger.getLogger(SafeHtmlTag.class);
private static final AntiSamy DEFAULT_ANTI_SAMY = new AntiSamy(loadPolicy(&amp;amp;quot;antisamy-default.xml&amp;amp;quot;));
private static final Map&amp;amp;lt;String, Policy&amp;amp;gt; POLICY_CACHE = new ConcurrentHashMap&amp;amp;lt;String, Policy&amp;amp;gt;();

private String text;
private String policyFile;

public void setText(String text) {
    this.text = text;
}

public void setPolicyFile(String policyFile) {
    this.policyFile = policyFile;
}

public int doStartTag() throws JspException {
    try {
        CleanResults scan = getAntiSamy().scan(text);
        if (scan.getNumberOfErrors() &amp;amp;gt; 0) {
            LOG.warn(&amp;amp;quot;antisamy encountered problem with input: &amp;amp;quot; + scan.getErrorMessages());
        }
        pageContext.getOut().print(scan.getCleanHTML());
    } catch (Exception e) {
        throw new IllegalStateException(e.getMessage(), e);
    }
    return SKIP_BODY;
}

public int doEndTag() throws JspException {
    return EVAL_PAGE;
}

protected AntiSamy getAntiSamy() {
    if (policyFile == null || &amp;amp;quot;&amp;amp;quot;.equals(policyFile)) {
        return DEFAULT_ANTI_SAMY;
    }
    return new AntiSamy(loadPolicy(policyFile));
}

private static Policy loadPolicy(String name) {
    if (POLICY_CACHE.containsKey(name)) {
        return POLICY_CACHE.get(name);
    }
    try {
        LOG.debug(&amp;amp;quot;Loading policy file '&amp;amp;quot; + name + &amp;amp;quot;' from classpath&amp;amp;quot;);
        URL url = SafeHtmlTag.class.getClassLoader().getResource(name);
        if (url == null || url.getFile() == null) {
            throw new FileNotFoundException(&amp;amp;quot;classpath file '&amp;amp;quot; + name + &amp;amp;quot;' was not found!&amp;amp;quot;);
        }
        Policy loadedPolicy = Policy.getInstance(url.getFile());
        POLICY_CACHE.put(name, loadedPolicy);
        return loadedPolicy;
    } catch (Exception e) {
        throw new IllegalStateException(e.getMessage(), e);
    }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tag implementation caches the loaded policy files internally as an optimization, and loads the policy
file called ‘antisamy-default.xml’ from the classpath if no custom policyFile is specified.
I’ve updated the source in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/barrypitman/antisamy-servlet-filter&quot;&gt;GitHub project&lt;/a&gt; from my
last post with this tag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope someone finds this useful!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Preventing XSS attacks with AntiSamy (Part 1)</title>
   <link href="http://barrypitman.github.com/2011/04/14/using-input-validation-XSS"/>
   <updated>2011-04-14T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://barrypitman.github.com/2011/04/14/using-input-validation-XSS</id>
   <content type="html">

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/exploits_of_a_mom.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2011/04/22/safe-and-clean-HTML-output-with-antisamy&quot;&gt;&amp;raquo; Skip to Part 2 &amp;raquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cross Site Scripting (XSS) attacks are a &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cross-site_scripting&quot;&gt;well&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/owaspantisamy/downloads/detail?name=Arshan%20Dabirsiaghi%20-%20Towards%20Malicious%20Code%20Detection%20and%20Removal.PDF&quot;&gt;documented&lt;/a&gt;
vulnerability affecting many web applications.
There has been a spate of high-profile &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theregister.co.uk/2011/03/29/mcafee_website_security_flaws/&quot;&gt;XSS&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theregister.co.uk/2010/09/22/twitter_xss_genesis/&quot;&gt;cases&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theregister.co.uk/2010/10/04/anti_virus_vendor_xss_snafu/&quot;&gt;recently&lt;/a&gt;.
Methods of protecting against these attacks depend on whether you want to accept any HTML formatted text from your
users or not:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Escape all user-supplied data on rendering&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t plan on accepting HTML input, you can simply escape all user-supplied data.
In a Java JSP application, this means outputting your text using the &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;c:out&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tag or &lt;code&gt;${fn:escapeXml(text)}&lt;/code&gt;
function instead of just &lt;code&gt;${text}&lt;/code&gt;. Once you’re in the habit of doing this, it might not be too bad,
however forgetting just one instance will leave your application vulnerable to attack.
Its easy to imagine a developer forgetting to escape some text while developing an email template.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Filter out invalid/malicious user-supplied data on submit&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do plan on accepting HTML input, you need to decide what type of input is allowed.
Many forums and applications using rich-text editors accept a limited subset of HTML from the user.
Most likely you’ll want to exclude/filter &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;script&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tags.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;p&gt;But there are many other tags/characters you would want to exclude too.
Just look at &lt;a href=&quot;http://ha.ckers.org/xss.html&quot;&gt;http://ha.ckers.org/xss.html&lt;/a&gt; to see some of the vast array of exploits,
and those are just the documented ones. Protecting against all possible attacks by exclusion is almost impossible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The preferred method is to specify what content the user is allowed to submit
(a whitelist as opposed to a blacklist), and filter/purify everything else.
Writing such a library is tricky at best, so go with a recognised, widely used solution.
&lt;a href=&quot;http://htmlpurifier.org/&quot;&gt;HTML Purifier&lt;/a&gt; for PHP and &lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/owaspantisamy/&quot;&gt;AntiSamy&lt;/a&gt; for Java/.NET
are two such solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;This is difficult!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Implementing either of the solutions above on a case-by-case basis would be a pain.
It gets in the way of what we really want to do, which is develop new features.
Ideally we would like a solution that protects the application and its users by default.
It would have been nice if the JSP default for outputting text with ${} was to escape it.
Then applications would be safe (to a large degree) from XSS attacks by default,
and we could un-escape text when we wanted to. Unfortunately that’s not the case.
Edit: &lt;a href=&quot;http://pukkaone.github.com/2011/01/03/jsp-cross-site-scripting-elresolver.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; is an article
describing how to override JSP EL expressions by default, though I haven’t tried it yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;A solution&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One solution is to implement a Java servlet filter which intercepts requests to the
server before they are processed, cleaning the submitted parameters using AntiSamy.
The application will only see the sanitized request parameters, so that the user-supplied
data is safe for re-display later. Assuming that you don’t already have malicious content
in your database, this approach should keep your users safe from XSS attacks, without you
needing to escape text every time you display it. Note however that for non-HTML formatted
text, you might as well escape user-supplied text as a precaution.
The advantage of using a filter is that it can very easily be applied to all requests and all
requests parameters, without your business logic having worry about cleaning submitted data.
The obvious disadvantage to using a filter-based approach is that it is more difficult to
cater for exceptions to the rule. AntiSamy policy files allow one to declare your own rules,
so you can be as strict or lax as you like. It’s difficult to imagine a scenario where a user submitting:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;username: &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;SCRIPT/XSS SRC=&quot;http://ha.ckers.org/xss.js&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/SCRIPT&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;would be ok!
Another disadvantage is the processing overhead of passing every request parameter through AntiSamy.
Although AntiSamy is designed for speed, my experience is that passing parameters through the
filter costs approximately 0.3ms per parameter on my machine (for shortish strings). For a large form
that might add up to 20ms or more. Depending on your application that may or may not be a problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Implementation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is my filter class, using a HttpServletRequestWrapper internally to override the &lt;code&gt;getParameter()&lt;/code&gt;-type methods:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src='https://gist.github.com/4557334.js?file=AntiSamyFilter.java'&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;/&lt;em&gt;*
 * Servlet filter that checks all request parameters for potential XSS attacks.
 * see http://bazageous.com/2011/04/14/preventing-xss-attacks-with-antisamy/
 *
 * @author barry pitman
 * @since 2011/04/12 5:13 PM
 &lt;/em&gt;/
public class AntiSamyFilter implements Filter {&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;private static final Logger LOG = Logger.getLogger(AntiSamyFilter.class);

/**
 * AntiSamy is unfortunately not immutable, but is threadsafe if we only call
 * {@link AntiSamy#scan(String taintedHTML, int scanType)}
 */
private final AntiSamy antiSamy;

public AntiSamyFilter() {
    try {
        URL url = this.getClass().getClassLoader().getResource(&amp;amp;quot;antisamy-slashdot-1.4.4.xml&amp;amp;quot;);
        Policy policy = Policy.getInstance(url.getFile());
        antiSamy = new AntiSamy(policy);
    } catch (PolicyException e) {
        throw new IllegalStateException(e.getMessage(), e);
    }
}

public void doFilter(ServletRequest request, ServletResponse response, FilterChain chain) throws IOException, ServletException {
    if (request instanceof HttpServletRequest) {
        CleanServletRequest cleanRequest = new CleanServletRequest((HttpServletRequest) request, antiSamy);
        chain.doFilter(cleanRequest, response);
    } else {
        chain.doFilter(request, response);
    }
}

public void init(FilterConfig filterConfig) throws ServletException {
}

public void destroy() {
}

/**
 * Wrapper for a {@link HttpServletRequest} that returns 'safe' parameter values by
 * passing the raw request parameters through the anti-samy filter. Should be private
 */
private static class CleanServletRequest extends HttpServletRequestWrapper {

    private final AntiSamy antiSamy;

    private CleanServletRequest(HttpServletRequest request, AntiSamy antiSamy) {
        super(request);
        this.antiSamy = antiSamy;
    }

    /**
     * overriding getParameter functions in {@link ServletRequestWrapper}
     */
    @Override
    public String[] getParameterValues(String name) {
        String[] originalValues = super.getParameterValues(name);
        if (originalValues == null) {
            return null;
        }
        List&amp;amp;lt;String&amp;amp;gt; newValues = new ArrayList&amp;amp;lt;String&amp;amp;gt;(originalValues.length);
        for (String value : originalValues) {
            newValues.add(filterString(value));
        }
        return newValues.toArray(new String[newValues.size()]);
    }

    @Override
    @SuppressWarnings(&amp;amp;quot;unchecked&amp;amp;quot;)
    public Map getParameterMap() {
        Map&amp;amp;lt;String, String[]&amp;amp;gt; originalMap = super.getParameterMap();
        Map&amp;amp;lt;String, String[]&amp;amp;gt; filteredMap = new ConcurrentHashMap&amp;amp;lt;String, String[]&amp;amp;gt;(originalMap.size());
        for (String name : originalMap.keySet()) {
            filteredMap.put(name, getParameterValues(name));
        }
        return Collections.unmodifiableMap(filteredMap);
    }

    @Override
    public String getParameter(String name) {
        String potentiallyDirtyParameter = super.getParameter(name);
        return filterString(potentiallyDirtyParameter);
    }

    /**
     * @param potentiallyDirtyParameter string to be cleaned
     * @return a clean version of the same string
     */
    private String filterString(String potentiallyDirtyParameter) {
        if (potentiallyDirtyParameter == null || &amp;amp;quot;&amp;amp;quot;.equals(potentiallyDirtyParameter)) {
            return potentiallyDirtyParameter;
        }

        try {
            CleanResults cr = antiSamy.scan(potentiallyDirtyParameter, AntiSamy.DOM);
            if (cr.getNumberOfErrors() &amp;amp;gt; 0) {
                LOG.warn(&amp;amp;quot;antisamy encountered problem with input: &amp;amp;quot; + cr.getErrorMessages());
            }
            return cr.getCleanHTML();
        } catch (Exception e) {
            throw new IllegalStateException(e.getMessage(), e);
        }
    }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Notes:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;This method will clean data submitted by regular form submissions from a browser.
If your application has other methods of data-input, e.g. a SOAP web service,
you will need to cater for that separately.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The filter will ‘modify’ the user-submitted data if it is deemed dangerous.
This is something to bear in mind when you are debugging.
The filter will at least log instances where inputs have been modified.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I haven’t tested it with file uploads so I’m not sure what effect, if any, that would have.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The implementation does not cache the filtered values, so calling request.getParameter(“name”)
twice will cause the value to be cleaned twice. Caching could be implemented if required.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’ve uploaded the source code as a maven project on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/barrypitman/antisamy-servlet-filter&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.
It includes a sample web application with simple JSP for testing the output of XSS hacks against the filter above, and a
maven-jetty-plugin configuration to get going quickly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is an application-level filter. You might also want to use a firewall,
e.g. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.modsecurity.org/&quot;&gt;mod_security&lt;/a&gt; for Apache for defence-in-depth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;Useful Resources:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/doctype/wiki/ArticleIntroductionToXSS&quot;&gt;http://code.google.com/p/doctype/wiki/ArticleIntroductionToXSS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.modsecurity.org/2008/07/do-you-know-how.html&quot;&gt;http://blog.modsecurity.org/2008/07/do-you-know-how.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ha.ckers.org/xss.html&quot;&gt;http://ha.ckers.org/xss.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Please let me know if you find any issues, or have suggestions for improvement!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>